Haneul Yoo

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

📞 +82-10-5269-2387 | 🖂 haneul.yoo@kaist.ac.kr | 🏕 haneul-yoo.github.io | 🖸 haneul-yoo | **in** haneulyoo | 💆 HaneulYoo13

About ___

Haneul Yoo is a Ph.D. student advised by Alice Oh in the School of Computing at KAIST. Her research interest primarily lies in the intersection of natural language processing and computational social science. In particular, she mainly works on (1) understanding historical documents in low-resource languages and (2) applying and utilizing NLP in language education. She believes there are still myriads of underrepresented languages in NLP, and our efforts on low-resource languages can build more culturally-diverse language models. She also believes language learners can contribute to NLP techniques and data and vice versa.

Education

KAIST Daejeon, Korea Ph.D. IN School of Computing Sep 2022 - CURRENT

• Advisor: Alice Oh

KAIST Daejeon, Korea Sep 2020 - Aug 2022

M.S. IN SCHOOL OF COMPUTING

· Advisor: Alice Oh

Ajou University Suwon, Korea

B.S. Double Major in Computer Science and Engineering and Digital Media, Graduation with Honors

• University of Wisconsin - Stout, WI, USA — Semester Abroad Winter 2018

Experience _____

LAMDA Lab Suwon, Korea

RESEARCH INTERN Mar 2020 - Aug 2020

• Study of Deep Learning Model for Bio-signal (EEG) Analysis

Advisor: Jungryul Seo and Kyung-Ah Sohn

KEPRI Daejeon, Korea

RESEARCH INTERN • Development of application services utilizing electric used power data

· Advisor: Moonsuk Choi

CSIRO OLD. Australia

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

• Convolutional deep neural network for detecting cattle in images/videos

· Advisor: Brano Kusy

Indielist Suwon, Korea

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & CO-FOUNDER

• Establishment of an independent music platform and development of iOS application services

Publications _

Rethinking Annotation: Can Language Learners Contribute?

HANEUL YOO, RIFKI AFINA PUTRI, CHANGYOON LEE, YOUNGIN LEE, SO-YEON AHN, DONGYEOP KANG, AND ALICE OH

RECIPE: How to Integrate ChatGPT into EFL Writing Education

Jieun Han*, **Haneul Yoo***, Yoonsu Kim, Junho Myung, Minsun Kim, Hyunseung Lim, Juho Kim, Tak Yeon Lee, HWAJUNG HONG, SO-YEON AHN, AND ALICE OH

Translating Hanja Historical Documents to Understandable Korean and English

JUHEE SON*, JIHO JIN*, **HANEUL YOO**, JINYEONG BAK, KYUNGHYUN CHO, AND ALICE OH

Jul 2023

Mar 2017 - Aug 2020

Sep 2019 - Feb 2020

Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

Jul 2023

Dec 2022

ACL 2023

L@S 2023, Work in Progress

EMNLP 2022, Findings

HUE: Pretrained Model and Dataset for Understanding Hanja Documents of Ancient Korea

HANEUL YOO, JIHO JIN, JUHEE SON, JINYEONG BAK, KYUNGHYUN CHO, AND ALICE OH

NAACL 2022, Findings

Jul 2022

Knowledge-Enhanced Evidence Retrieval for Counterargument Generation

YOHAN JO, **HANEUL YOO**, JINYEONG BAK, ALICE OH, CHRIS REED, AND EDUARD HOVY

EMNLP 2021, Findings

Nov 2021

Image-based Deep Learning Approach for EEG Signal Classification

HANEUL YOO, JUNGRYUL SEO, AND KYUNG-AH SOHN

KICS Summer Conference 2020

Aug 2020

Proposal and Simulation of Optimal Electric Vehicle Routing Algorithm

MOONSUK CHOI, INJI CHOI, MINHAE JANG, AND HANEUL YOO

KEPCO 2020

Mar 2020

Talks

Guest Lecturer Al Tech Boostcamp, "Some Points that We Should Consider about Data-Centric NLP" (May 2023)

Guest Lecturer Al Tech Boostcamp, "The Data You Created, Are You Sure It's Okay?" (Dec 2022)

Teaching Experiences _____

Al Tech Boostcamp (Spring 2023, Fall 2022) at NAVER Connect Foundation

Al Ethics (Spring 2023), Al and Its Social Impact (Spring 2023), KAIST SoC Colloquium (Fall 2021), Machine Learning (Fall 2022, TA

Spring 2021) at KAIST

Python (Spring 2020) at Suwon Information Science High School, Java (Spring 2019) at Maetan High School Teacher

Academic Services

Volunteer FAccT (2022), COLING (2022) **Reviewer** NeurIPS (2021, 2023), EMNLP (2022)

Honors and Awards

Outstanding Volunteer Award

KAIST Support Scholarship

KAIST

Aug 2020

Sep 2020 - Current

Graduation with Honors

Ajou University

SUMMA CUM LAUDE (1ST PLACE)

Gyeonggi Volunteer Center

Jun 2020

Special Prize

BIXPO

BIXPO 2019

Nov 2019

Excellence Award

KIPA

CREATIVE START-UP COMPETITION

Nov 2019

Academic Excellence Scholarship

Asan Foundation Mar 2017 - Aug 2020

References _____

Alice Oh Professor in School of Computing, KAIST